Hello everybody. Welcome to Week 3!
This is my favorite part of the course as we are going to work
with graphics. You will learn to
draw simple shapes into the new HTML5 canvas
elements. We will see along many examples
how to draw lines, curves, circles,
arcs, images, how to fill shapes with
textures, patterns, repetitive patterns
with gradiants, how to add shadows
and so on. The course comes with many small examples,
so do not be afraid by its length.
This time the course is long but there is no major difficulties in it.
You will also learn a lot of good practices.
You will learn how to use geometric transformations,
how to make a responsive canvas, and how to write
a multiple image loader and this is a bit
the tricky part usually for beginners.
The canvas API is simple but rich, and this week covers
all the things you need to draw graphics.
I hope you enjoyed the course so far and I'll meet you next week
for a very funny part that is about animation.